Hiroko Yamaji Front-end Engineer

+81-80-8452-9789 | hiroko@hirokoymj.com | Tokyo, Japan

Professional Profile

With 15 years of experience as a Front-end engineer in Los Angeles and 3 years in Japan, I am excited to return to the US job market. Currently, I am seeking a position as a Software Engineer or a role related to Google Cloud. I am open to relocating to California, Arizona (Phoenix area) or Texas. Proficient in React.js and GraphQL.

Code Sample

https://www.hirokoymj.com https://github.com/hirokoymj/hiroko-web-frontend

US Status

Green Card

Technical Skills

Front-end: JavaScript, React.js, Redux, Apollo Client v3, Lodash, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, Material UI v4

Back-end: Typescript, Node.js, Apollo Server v3, Mongoose **Database**: MongoDB Atlas, Cloud Databases on Google Cloud

Cloud Platform: Google Cloud, Heroku Version Control: Git, GitHub, GitLab

Software: Visual Studio Code, Apollo Studio, Slack, Google Meet, Microsoft Teams, JIRA, Confluence

Work Experience

Infosys Limited Japan Tokyo, Japan

May 2022 - Present

Google Cloud Technical Support Agent (August 2022 – Present)

- Work in the platform team specialized in Serverless, Cloud Database and Storage on Google Cloud.
- Reproduce customer issues in a test cloud environment for troubleshooting.
- Organize the causes of issues and report the details to customers politely.

Frontend Engineer (May 2022 – August 2022)

- Architected a new web application using React, Redux and i18n for a Japanese life insurance company.
- Provided Japanese language support for offshore members.

Asurion Japan Tokyo, Japan

May 2021 – January 2022

Frontend Engineer (Contractor)

- Utilized React.js, Redux, TypeScript, Apollo client and GraphQL.
- Developed a new feature for the call center web app.
- Conducted React component testing by Cypress.

HyreCar Inc. Los Angeles, CA

January 2019 – December 2020

- Utilized React.js, Redux, React Hooks, React Router, JavaScript, Apollo client and Material UI.
- Dedicated to working on the features for the Owner app, such as the claim form flow and Google Map API, while collaborating with other developers using Git.
- Assigned coding tasks through JIRA and raised pull requests to GitLab.

Beachbody.com Santa Monica, CA

December 2017 - September 2018

Frontend Engineer

- Utilized JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, JavaScript, Gulp.js, Bootstrap 3 grid system and React.js.
- Build responsive web pages and an image carousel using Bootstrap 3 and JavaScript.

Strategic Partners Inc. Northridge, CA

December 2016 – June 2017

Frontend Engineer

- Utilized JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, Sass, Gulp.js, Bootstrap 3, React.js and OpenWeather API.
- Transformed a non-responsive website into a fully responsive one using grid system.
- Built weather data component with the weather API to display local weather information.

Teleflora.com Los Angeles, CA

October 2009 – October 2016

Frontend Developer

- Utilized HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Sass, Gulp.js, Bootstrap3 and PHP.
- Created responsive landing pages with a promo code for the US holidays to facilitate sales.

MC Squared Los Angeles, CA

September 2006 – November 2007

Web Developer (Full Stack)

- Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL.
- Developed a CMS (Content Management System) in PHP, allowing customers to update website content.

Sony Electronics Inc. Santa Monica, CA

July 2005 – July 2006

Web Developer (Contractor)

• Utilized HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Java, JDK 4.0 and MySQL.

Education

Santa Monica College Santa Monica, CA Certificate of Interactive Media February 2004 - June 2005

Yamawaki Gakuen Junior College Tokyo Japan Associate degree of Food Science

April 1989 – March 1991

Certifications

Google Cloud Certified Professional Cloud Architect

January 2024

• Google Cloud Certified Professional Cloud Database Engineer

July 2023

• Google Certified Cloud Associate Cloud Engineer

January 2023